Guide to the Bill Johnston Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Bill Johnston papers
approximately 1970-2000
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
6235
6235-001
Johnston, Bill$c(Union organizer)
2.28 cubic feet 2 boxes
Workshop training materials from an organizer with the United Food and Commercial Workers local unions in Washington State.
William “Bill” Johnston is a retired staff organizer of the United Food and Commercial Workers in Washington state. Bill Johnston has worked in unions in both the private and public sectors. He spent 30 years as an organizer, local union president, international trustee and district council president for five northwestern states, and served on the health and welfare and pension boards of several unions. He retired in 2003 and lives in Tacoma, Washington. He is a member of the National Writers Union (Pacific Northwest Chapter).
Workshop training materials from Bill Johnston’s career working as an organizer with the United Food and Commercial Workers local unions in Washington State.
No restrictions on access.
William Johnston via Ross Rieder.
Johnston, Bill$c(Union organizer)$xArchives; United Food and Commercial Workers International Union$xArchives; Labor$zWashington (State); Labor unions$zWashington (State); Labor movement$zWashington (State); Collective labor agreements$zWashington (State); Conference materials; Collective labor agreements; Handbooks and manuals; Records (Documents); Ephemera; Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor Unions; Washington (State)
- Labor-Management Cooperation Conference, 1989 (Box 1)
  Conference Materials
- Working Families Health Care Campaign, 1998 (Box 1)
- American Federation State, County and Municipal Employees Council, Undated (Box 1)
- United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Manual for Committee Members, Undated (Box 1)
  Manual
- United Food and Commercial Workers Union Regional Education Conference (Part 1 of 2), 1985 (Box 1)
- United Food and Commercial Workers Union Regional Education Conference (Part 2 of 2), 1985 (Box 1)
- Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union Shop Steward Program, ca. 1993 (Box 1)
- "Union Security After Beck" Conference, 1993 (Box 1)
- International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Union Steward Resource Manual (Part 1 of, ca. 1985 (Box 1)
  District Lodge 751
- International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Union Steward Resource Manual, ca. 1985 (Box 1)
- Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees, New Hotel Development Training, 1999 (Box 1)
- Seattle Times Contract Review, 1990 (Box 1)
  Contract
- Updated Seattle Times Contract, 1990 (Box 1)
- Seattle Times Contract, 1997 (Box 1)
- Horvitz Newspapers, Inc. Profit Sharing Plan, 1995 (Box 1)
- Contract Between Westmedia Corporation & Communication Workers of America, 1999 (Box 1)
- Scott Paper Company Contract Offer, 1994 (Box 1)
- Hotel Employees Restaurant Employees Pattern Agreement, 2002 (Box 1)
- Contract Between Communication Workers of America & Sun Publishing Company, 1995 (Box 1)
- Contract Between City of Mercer Island and City Employees, 1995 (Box 1)
- Washington Employers, Inc. Information, ca. 1995 (Box 1)
  Onboarding Information
- Incentive Plan Philosphy for the Seattle Times Advertising Department, 1995 (Box 1)
- Memorandum of Understanding Regarding Job Sharing between The Seattle Times and Pacific Northwest Newspaper Guild, 1994 (Box 1)
- Memorandum of Understanding Regarding Job Sharing between The Seattle Times and Pacific Northwest Newspaper Guild, 1994 (Box 1)
- Contract between the Aeronatical Industrial District Lodge and..., 1995 (Box 1)
- Contract Between UFCW Local 1001 and Pacific Northwest Newspaper Guild, 1997 (Box 1)
- Guild Contract between the Yakima Herald-Republic, Inc and the Yakima Newspaper Guild, 1992 (Box 1)
- Labor Agreement Between Bremerton Printing Company and Communications Workers of America, 1996 (Box 1)
- Newspaper Agreement between the Communications Workers of America Union Local No. 14761 and the Daily Herald Company, 1993 (Box 1)
- Agreement Between Communication Workers of America #14761 and the Daily Journal of Commerca, 1995 (Box 1)
- Labor Agreement Between Renton Printery, Inc and Communications Workers of America, Local 14761, ca. 1992 (Box 1)
- Public Employee CONFERENCE [part 1], 1984-1990 (Box 1)
  Materials from 1990 conference--includes readings from other dates (1984, 1987)
- Public Employee CONFERENCE [part 2], 1984-1990 (Box 1)
  Materials from 1990 conference--includes readings from other dates (1984, 1987). Part one is material from binder front pocket
- Public Employee CONFERENCE [part 3], 1984-1990 (Box 1)
- Stewards Resource Manual: Communications Workers of America, 1989 (Box 1)
  Binder contained "Building Union on the Job" Steward's Training copyright 1989
- United Food Commercial Workers / Local 555 / Staff Training Manual / Labor Education & Research Center University of Oregon [part 1], 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  "A Short History of American Labor" excerpted from AFL-CIO publication
- United Food Commercial Workers / Local 555 / Staff Training Manual / Labor Education & Research Center University of Oregon [part 2], 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  "Local 555 / United Food Commercial Workers / AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations) / Staff Training Program / Presented by Labor Education and Research Center, University of Oregon, Eugene / September 15-20, 1985 Training program materials--contains wide variety of materials: articles, white papers, bios, appeals court findings
- United Food Commercial Workers / Local 555 / Staff Training Manual / Labor Education & Research Center University of Oregon [part 3], 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  "Local 555 / United Food Commercial Workers / AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations) / Staff Training Program / Presented by Labor Education and Research Center, University of Oregon, Eugene / September 15-20, 1985 (ctd.)
- United Food Commercial Workers / Local 555 / Staff Training Manual / Labor Education & Research Center University of Oregon [part 4], 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  Interesting "zine"-type item: How to run a union meeting / Workers compensation facts booklet
- Budget / Ex(ecutive) Committee Monthly Reports [part 1], 1994-1997 (Box 1)
  Tabs: MEETING AGENDA, MINUTES, PER CAP Reports, Budget (also correspondence)
- Budget / Ex(ecutive) Committee Monthly Reports [part 2], 1994-1997 (Box 2)
  Tab: MONTHLY Budget
- WPEA (Washington Public Employees Association) Leading the Way [part 1], 1991-2002 (Box 2)
  Contact lists for WPEA (Washington Public Employees Association), "WPEA Job Representative/Shop Steward Guide", other
- WPEA (Washington Public Employees Association) Leading the Way [part 2], 1991-2002 (Box 2)
  StreetHeat--Mobilizing to Win: A Guide to Revitalizing the Labor Movement by Mobilizing Members in Communities Across America (AFL-CIO/American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations); Communications Workers of America: Mobilizing for the '90s; Getting Organized: A guide to how your union is built (WPEA)
- Issues in Collective Bargaining: Service Industries / Service Employees International Union, AFL-CIO (American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations), CLC (Canadian Labour Congress ?), 1981-1982 (Box 2)
- Keeping the Record Straight: How to meet your local union's reporting, financial, record-keeping and other obligations, Undated (Box 2)
- UFCW Local 555 staff training: collective barganing workshop, 1998 (Box 2)
- Resource Manual: Stewards, Communications Workers of America, 1994 (Box 2)
- "Union Cities Planning Guide for Central Labor Councils", 1997 (Box 2)
- 1997 AFL-CIO Program Summary, 1996 (Box 2)
- The Information Superhighway: Exploring Strategies for Workers, Summary of Conference Sessions, 1995 (Box 2)
- "It's Time for Management Concessions", 1983 (Box 2)
- Talking to Union Leaders about Smart Growth, Undated (Box 2)
- Common Sense Economics: The Basic Rap, AFL-CIO Economics Education Project, 1997 (Box 2)
- Changing Work: A Union Guide to Workplace Change, 1994 (Box 2)
- Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union Officers' Report, 1996 (Box 2)
- High Hopes, Little Trust: A Study of Young Workers and their Ups and Downs in the New Economy, 1999 (Box 2)
- High Road Partnerships Report, Undated (Box 2)
- Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Shop Steward Manual, Undated (Box 2)
- International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers: High Performance Work Organization Partnership, 1994 (Box 2)
- Letter from Robert Birge to Ronald Kurvnik on grievance of Lisa Hubbard, 1988 (Box 2)
- Economic Development, AFL-CIO Human Resources Development Institute, 1998 (Box 2)
- Seattle Times/ Gewspaper Guild contract document, 1990-1995 (Box 2)
- Service Employees International Union training workshop materials, 1998 (Box 2)
- Communication Workers of America printshop contracts, 1987-1994 (Box 2)
- Shop steward manuals, 1998, undated (Box 2)
- United Food and Commerical Workers: organizing seminar, 1987 (Box 2)
- United Food and Commericial Workers International Union Local 555: union representative training, 1998 (Box 2)
- Service Employees International Union conference: the employer offensive, 1981 (Box 2)
- United Food and Commericial Workers Counvil No. 17/ Action 84, 1984 (Box 2)
- United Food and Commercial Workers/ brochures, 1986-1988 (Box 2)
- TH Research, INC. A survey of the membership of the United Food and Commercial workers, 1982 (Box 2)
- TH Research, INC. A survey of the membership of the United Food and Commercial workers in Oregon and Washington, 1984 (Box 2)
- Posters and Brochures, ca. 1990s (Box 2)
- Washington State memo on union organizational efforts to agency directors, 2002 (Box 2)
- Evergreen Negotiations Workshop, ca. 1989 (Box 2)
- United Food and Commercial Workers International Union, undated (Box 2)
- UFCW booklets, undated (Box 2)
- The Organizing Campaign- Service Employees International, undated (Box 2)
- Barganing your SEIU contract- textbook and resource material- Service Employees International, collective barganing manual, undated (Box 2)